[
  {
    "question": "el almuerzo",
    "answer": "das Mittagessen"
  },
  {
    "question": "el pastel / la torta",
    "answer": "der Kuchen"
  },
  {
    "question": "la semana laboral",
    "answer": "die Arbeitswoche"
  },
  {
    "question": "los colegas",
    "answer": "die Kollegen"
  },
  {
    "question": "la bebida",
    "answer": "das Getränk"
  },
  {
    "question": "la tarjeta",
    "answer": "die Karte"
  },
  {
    "question": "el juego de mesa",
    "answer": "das Brettspiel"
  },
  {
    "question": "la actividad",
    "answer": "die Aktivität"
  },
  {
    "question": "España",
    "answer": "Spanien"
  },
  {
    "question": "Italia",
    "answer": "Italien"
  },
  {
    "question": "Austria",
    "answer": "Österreich"
  },
  {
    "question": "Francia",
    "answer": "Frankreich"
  },
  {
    "question": "la navidad",
    "answer": "das Weihnachten"
  },
  {
    "question": "la fiesta",
    "answer": "die Party"
  },
  {
    "question": "el plato / el platillo",
    "answer": "das Gericht"
  },
  {
    "question": "la carne",
    "answer": "das Fleisch"
  },
  {
    "question": "el pollo",
    "answer": "das Huhn"
  },
  {
    "question": "la carne de res",
    "answer": "das Rindfleisch"
  },
  {
    "question": "el queso",
    "answer": "der Käse"
  },
  {
    "question": "la verdura",
    "answer": "das Gemüse"
  },
  {
    "question": "la cebolla",
    "answer": "die Zwiebel"
  },
  {
    "question": "la zanahoria",
    "answer": "die Karotte"
  },
  {
    "question": "la patata",
    "answer": "der Erdapfel"
  },
  {
    "question": "el tomate",
    "answer": "der Paradeiser"
  },
  {
    "question": "el pimiento",
    "answer": "der Paprika"
  },
  {
    "question": "la espinaca",
    "answer": "der Spinat"
  },
  {
    "question": "el horno",
    "answer": "der Ofen"
  },
  {
    "question": "la sartén",
    "answer": "die Pfanne"
  },
  {
    "question": "la receta",
    "answer": "das Rezept"
  },
  {
    "question": "la calabaza",
    "answer": "der Kürbis"
  },
  {
    "question": "el pepino",
    "answer": "die Gurke"
  },
  {
    "question": "la berenjena",
    "answer": "die Aubergine"
  },
  {
    "question": "el calabacín",
    "answer": "die Zucchini"
  },
  {
    "question": "el brócoli",
    "answer": "der Brokkoli"
  },
  {
    "question": "la col",
    "answer": "der Kohl"
  },
  {
    "question": "la especia",
    "answer": "das Gewürz"
  },
  {
    "question": "el aceite",
    "answer": "das Öl"
  },
  {
    "question": "la sal",
    "answer": "das Salz"
  },
  {
    "question": "la pimienta",
    "answer": "der Pfeffer"
  },
  {
    "question": "el ajo",
    "answer": "der Knoblauch"
  },
  {
    "question": "la ensalada",
    "answer": "der Salat"
  },
  {
    "question": "el vino",
    "answer": "der Wein"
  },
  {
    "question": "la cerveza",
    "answer": "das Bier"
  },
  {
    "question": "el zumo de fruta",
    "answer": "der Obstsaft"
  },
  {
    "question": "la botella",
    "answer": "die Flasche"
  },
  {
    "question": "el país",
    "answer": "das Land"
  },
  {
    "question": "cocinar",
    "answer": "kochen"
  },
  {
    "question": "hornear",
    "answer": "backen"
  },
  {
    "question": "celebrar",
    "answer": "feiern"
  },
  {
    "question": "comprar",
    "answer": "kaufen"
  },
  {
    "question": "jugar",
    "answer": "spielen"
  },
  {
    "question": "tener",
    "answer": "haben"
  },
  {
    "question": "venir",
    "answer": "kommen"
  },
  {
    "question": "trabajar",
    "answer": "arbeiten"
  },
  {
    "question": "hacer",
    "answer": "machen"
  },
  {
    "question": "ser/estar",
    "answer": "sein"
  },
  {
    "question": "gustar",
    "answer": "mögen"
  },
  {
    "question": "cortar",
    "answer": "schneiden"
  },
  {
    "question": "freír/asar",
    "answer": "braten"
  },
  {
    "question": "asar a la parrilla",
    "answer": "grillen"
  },
  {
    "question": "comer",
    "answer": "essen"
  },
  {
    "question": "beber",
    "answer": "trinken"
  },
  {
    "question": "georgiano",
    "answer": "georgisch"
  },
  {
    "question": "europeo",
    "answer": "europäisch"
  },
  {
    "question": "caro",
    "answer": "teuer"
  },
  {
    "question": "delicioso",
    "answer": "lecker"
  }
]